Guide to the Brooklyn photograph and illustration collection ARC.202
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn photograph and illustration collection
circa 1850 to 2010
Brooklyn Historical Society
ARC.202
9.6 Linear Feet in 21 manuscript boxes, six oversize boxes, and one flat file folder.
The Brooklyn photograph and illustration collection contains approximately 7000 items dating from the mid 19th century to the beginning of the 21st.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The bulk of the collection was formalized into a collection in 1973, but material was collected throughout the 20th century and into the 21st from various news agencies, magazines, journals, and other print publications, as well as from other sources.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two groups. "Images with object IDS" consists of photographs that are numbered by accession number. Accession V1973.005 accounts for the majority of this group, along with V1973.006. The second group, "Images by subject," is unnumbered and is arranged alphabetically by subject. Item-level description for the images with object IDS is available in the library's image database, PastPerfect.
Other Finding Aids
Item-level description and digital versions of images with object IDs are available for searching via the image database in the library.
A full index of subjects in accessions V1973.005, V1973.006, and the "prints by subject" section is available in paper form in the library.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn photograph and illustration collection contains approximately 7000 items dating from the mid 19th century to the beginning of the 21st. The collection provides comprehensive visual documentation of the borough of Brooklyn, N.Y., with images of neighborhoods, homes, buildings, businesses, parks, the waterfront, and infrastructure. Subjects of interest include aerial views of Brooklyn, major local banks, armories, bridges, churches, civic groups, libraries, museums, schools, parks, railroads, subway stations, and city and government agencies such as prisons, fire and police departments, and post offices. Over 30 Brooklyn neighborhoods are documented, including Brownstone Brooklyn, Williamsburg, Greenpoint, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Bushwick, Crown Heights, Brownsville, Canarsie, Flatlands, Sheepshead Bay, Gravesend, Coney Island, Bay Ridge, Sunset Park, Borough Park, and Flatbush. In addition to images of the Brooklyn Navy Yard (formally known as the New York Naval Shipyard), the collection also contains photographs of Brooklyn docks, harbors, and ferries.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Photographs; Aerial photographs; Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Dwellings |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.); Sea Gate (New York, N.Y.); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Park South (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Illustrations (layout features); Gerritsen Beach (New York, N.Y.); Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Flatlands (New York, N.Y.); Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Cobble Hill (New York, N.Y.); Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.); Waterfronts |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bath Beach (New York, N.Y.); Dyker Heights (New York, N.Y.); Panoramas; Borough Park (New York, N.Y.); Manhattan Beach (New York, N.Y.); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.); Gowanus (New York, N.Y.); Brighton Beach (New York, N.Y.); Banks and banking |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Armories |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Gravesend (New York, N.Y.); New Utrecht (New York, N.Y.); New Lots (New York, N.Y.); Civic improvement |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Canarsie (New York, N.Y.); Libraries |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Bridges |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Church buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Railroads |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sheepshead Bay (New York, N.Y.); Museums |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.); Schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Prisons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Subway stations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Fire departments |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Police |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Post office buildings |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |v Pictorial works; Black-and-white prints (prints on paper); Black-and-white prints (photographs); Exterior views; Studio portraits; Interior views; Cemeteries |z United States; Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.) |v Pictorial works; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Fire fighters |z New York (State) |z New York; New York Naval Shipyard
- Images by Object ID
  - V1973.5.1 - V1973.5.279 (Box 1)
  - V1973.5.280 - V1973.5.529 (Box 2)
  - V1973.5.530 - V1973.5.749 (Box 3)
  - V1973.5.750 - V1973.5.999 (Box 4)
  - V1973.5.1000 - V1973.5.1249 (Box 5)
  - V1973.5.1250 - V1973.5.1539 (Box 6)
  - V1973.5.1540 - V1973.5.1829 (Box 7)
  - V1973.5.1830 - V1973.5.2169 (Box 8)
  - V1973.5.2170 - V1973.5.2569 (Box 9)
  - V1973.5.2570 - V1973.5.2969 (Box 10)
  - V1973.5.2580 (Box 26)
  - V1973.5.2970 - V1973.5.3389 (Box 11)
  - V1973.5.3390 - V1973.5.3734 (Box 12)
  - V1973.6.1 - V1973.6.459 (Box 13)
  - V1973.6.460 - V1973.6.773 (Box 14)
  - V1973.6.745-758 (Box 24)
  - V1991.12.1-3, 9-10 (Folder Flat File)
  - V1991.12.4-8, 11-15 (Box 26)
  - V1992.32.1-2, 4, 6 (Box 26)
  - V1991.32.3, 5 (Box 24)
  - V1991.32.8, 9, 11 (Box 22)
  - V1997.66 (Box 24)
- Images by Subject
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, and is open for research without restrictions. This series has not been digitized.
  - African Americans (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - American Revolution (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Animals (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Architecture (Box 15, Folder 4, Box 25)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes an image of a model of a pediment from the Dime Savings Bank of Brooklyn.
  - Armories (Box 15, Folder 5)
    One image of the Brooklyn armory at 52nd Street and 2nd Avenue.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Donated by Patricia Knox.
  - Army - People, Wight, G.W. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    One image of Jerry Strickland, son of Johnathan Strickland, son of Harmon Strickland.
    Gift of G.W. Wight, 1954.
    Wight, G.W.
  - Artwork (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Asian Americans (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Photographs by Rex Chen, a photographer hired by BHS for an exhibition on Sunset Park.
  - Aviation - Airmail planes, Underwood & Underwood; Dewell, Nathaniel L.; P. & A. Photo (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Aviation - Airplanes, Underwood & Underwood (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Aviation - Airports, Trans World Airlines; Hess Bros.; Underwood & Underwood; Kingsborough Historical Society; Skyviews, New York (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Trans World Airlines; Kingsborough Historical Society
  - Aviation - Dirigibles, Underwood & Underwood (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Aviation - People, Underwood & Underwood (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Bay Ridge (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Includes a black and white photograph of Bay Ridge High School (now PS 485 High School of Telecommunication Arts and Technology) and a color print of a private residence on 82nd Street.
  - Bedford Stuyvesant (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Includes a photograph of buildings on Herkimer Street circa 1921 and a circa 19th century print of buildings on Gates Avenue.
  - Bensonhurst (Box 15, Folder 16)
    One 1888 black and white photograph of a steam train at Bensonhurst station.
  - Bergen Beach (Box 15, Folder 17)
    One black and white photograph of Bergen Beach seen from the water, 1918.
    Gift of Harry Seeback, 1975.
  - Boerum Hill (Box 15, Folder 18)
    One of the two photographs in this folder is labeled "from H. Dickson McKenna."
  - Bridges (Box 15, Folder 19, Box 22)
  - Brooklyn - General (Box 15, Folder 20)
    One book of photo postcards depicting Brooklyn landmarks by A. Wittemann, copyright 1903.
    Gift of Edward Sack, 2010.
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music (Box 15, Folder 21)
    3 prints from periodicals.
  - Brooklyn Dodgers (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn Eagle Statue (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1750-1850 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1851-1865 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1865-1900 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1900-1920 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    Includes one advertising booklet about "Mansion House," an apartment building on Hicks Street between Clark and Pierrepont.
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1920-1940 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    Includes one image of 142 Joralemon Street, architect Philip Freshman.
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1940-1960 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    Includes three portrait photographs in Hotel Bossert souvenir folders.
  - Brooklyn Heights, 1980-2000 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Brooklyn Heights - Church of Holy Trinity (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Brooklyn Navy Yard (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Also includes Wallabout Market.
  - Buildings, Houses - Dutch Homesteads, Dillard, Maude Esther; Spies, Leo C. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Some of the images in this folder are labeled "from Maude E. Dillard."
    Includes Breevort, Vanderveer, Wyckoff-Bennett, Martense, Ditmas, Duryea, Lott, Neefus. One image of the Bevier house is by Leo C. Spies.
    Dillard, Maude Esther
  - Buildings, Houses - Identified (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Addresses include 1781 East 15th Street, 511 Greene Avenue, 2358 West 12th Street, 1215 Dunne Court. Also includes Foster house, New York Telephone Co. building, Malcolm MacKinnon residence.
  - Buildings, Houses - Unidentified, Bursten, Walter (Box 16, Folder 4)
    One of the photographs is stamped with the name and address of Walter Bursten.
    Bursten, Walter
  - Business and Commerce - Advertisements (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Business and Commerce - Bars and Restaurants (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Business and Commerce - Business (Box 16, Folder 7, Box 22)
    One photograph is of people in the office of Pendleton and Pendleton, Inc. at 135 Montague Street circa 1925, donated by Margaret Menard Price, whose father Albert Robert Menard (d. 1987) was president of the company.
    Also includes Leonard Moody real estate office, Dime Savings Bank, Williamsburg Savings Bank building, and an image of the truck of Frank Waring, lace curtain refinisher, donated by Thomas Ahern, August 1993.
    Box 22 includes "A Hot Summer Day," 1995, which was a gift of Phyllis Starkman in 2017 and is a color photo of Heights Cinema, as well as images of Kings County Savings Bank and Grand Opera House.
    Related Materials
    There is an additional image of Frank Waring filed under Transportation - Horses.
  - Business and Commerce - Commerce (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Business and Commerce - Factories/ Industrial (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Includes Empire Stores (Marcia Reiss photos), Bush Terminal, Socony Vacuum Oil Co. (Mobil).
  - Business and Commerce - Labor Movements (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Copies of two images from the Sam Reiss Photographs, Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, NYU. One depicts a picket line outside Beth-El hospital and the other Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. speaking at an event for Local 1199, Drug and Hospital Employees.
  - Business and Commerce - Ladder Companies (Box 16, Folder 11, Box 22)
    One photograph that was the gift of Patricia Knox. Another depicts "Bridge Street Colored Church" with scaffolding on its front facade.
  - Business and Commerce - Merchants and Vendors (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Includes two photos of horse-drawn carts that were the gift of Bob Mickert and an image of a horse-drawn cart from Frederick Loeser's.
  - Business and Commerce - Mills (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Business and Commerce - Women at work (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Cemeteries - Greenwood (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Churches - Buildings (Box 16, Folder 16, Box 22)
    Includes images of Christ Church (Bay Ridge), Old Bushwick Church, Dutch Reformed Church of Flatbush, and Third M.E. Church, Washington Street, stamped "Armbruster collection" on verso.
    Box 22 includes Holy Cross Cloister.
  - Churches - Congregants (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Includes Sunday Services at Charity R.C. Church in Crown Heights by Rodney K. Hurley, Junior Choir of the Middle Collegiate Church.
  - Churches - Plymouth Church (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Most of the photographs in this folder are credited to either Roy Pinney or Boro Wide Photos.
  - Civic Organizations (Box 17, Folder 2, Box 22)
    Includes Red Cross Auxiliary of the Reformed Church of Flatbush (1944) and the Borinquen Democratic Club.
    Box 22 includes images of the National Area Health Education Center Organization (pictured at Borough Hall) and the Third Congress of American Poets (1938; V1998.9.6).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Many of the photographs in Box 22 are rolled and may be inaccessible to researchers.
  - Civic Organizations - Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce (Box 17, Folder 3, Box 22)
    Includes images of a 1930 women's dinner attended by Eleanor Roosevelt, a circa 1924 golf tournament, and a circa 1927 West Indies cruise.
    Box 22 includes an image of Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce members with President Coolidge at the White House, April 1927.
    The photograph in Box 22 is rolled and may not be accessible to researchers.
  - Clubs and Associations (Box 17, Folder 4, Box 22)
    Includes images of Daughters of the American Revolution Battle Pass chapter 50th anniversary (1955, photo by R.H. White); Morse Telegraph Club (1964, gift of Joseph B. Milgram); Greenpoint Patriotic League (1944); Lincoln Public Speaking Club (1927-1929); Long Island Tercentenary Committee; Long Island Linksmen; Long Island Fair; Whig and Tory Day; Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall; Knickerbocker Field Club; Brooklyn Tennis Club; Brooklyn Safety Council; Brooklyn Real Estate Board; Brooklyn Democratic Committee; Todd Memorial Post #1201 American Legion (1946).
    Box 22 includes images of the National Association of Organists.
    Daughters of the American Revolution. Battle Pass Chapter (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Knickerbocker Field Club; Flatbush Civic and Cultural Association. Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall; Brooklyn Real Estate Board (New York, N.Y.)
  - Cobble Hill (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Coney Island, 19th century (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Also includes Brighton Beach.
  - Coney Island, 1900-1950 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Includes an image of the Manhattan Beach hotel. Also includes a souvenir image of Henry and Rose Haber circa 1916 that was the gift of Frances Haber.
  - Coney Island, 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    One photograph of the Parachute Jump circa 1955 by Harry Kalmus.
  - Coney Island, circa 1980s (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Includes two photographs: Polar Bear Club by Frank Passalagua and Coney Island Bayview Gardens Astella Development Corp. by Stephen Senigo (1985).
  - Dinners and banquets (Box 23)
    Many of the photographs under this subject are rolled and may be inaccessible to researchers.
    Includes Brooklyn Rotary Club Dodgers lunch (1945); YWCA 75th anniversary (1963; Gift of Frederick C. Ward, 1994); Catholic Men's League of New York Navy Yard (1943); Morning Choral luncheons and dinners (1927, 1932, 1935, 1937, 1938, 1940, 1949, 1954); A. Schrader & Sons Co. testimonial dinner for Miss M. Forbes (Gift of Irene Kasika Jansky); Brooklyn Council, Boy Scouts of America (V1995.039); Flushing Oratorio Society (1936); 12:45 Club (1940, 1948); New York Federated Music Clubs (1948).
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1750-1850 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    One illustration of Borough Hall.
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1850-1900 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Mostly images of Borough Hall with one image of "shanties at the foot of Court Street."
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1900-1920 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1920-1950 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Downtown Brooklyn, 1950-1980 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Borough Hall and county courthouse.
  - Dumbo (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Color photographs from Marcia Reiss, 2002; Empire Stores, circa 1970.
  - Engineering and Construction (Box 17, Folder 16)
    One circa 19th century image of what appears to be sewer pipes on the street.
  - Farm Life (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Includes Lefferts, Boerum and Vanderveer barns.
  - Fire Department (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Includes photos of pictures from an 1892 history of the Brooklyn Fire Department that were the gift of Mike Gorman and Museum of the City of New York picture postcards of fire engines and carriages that were the gift of H.M. Nicholson, 1956.
  - Fire Destruction (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Flatbush (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Flatlands (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Includes Stoothoff, Lott, Remsen, and Bergen residences.
  - Fort Greene (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Fort Hamilton (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Forts (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Gay Life (Box 17, Folder 25)
    One set of black and white photos of the Stonewall project, September 1992. Several copies of one photo of a meeting of the East Coast Homophile Organization (ECHO), 1965, Jack Nichols collection.
  - Gowanus (Box 17, Folder 26)
    Schermerhorn house; Old Stone House; view from Battle Hill.
  - Gravesend (Box 17, Folder 27)
    Mural of Lady Moody that hung in Greater New York Savings Bank, Bay Parkway and 67th Street, until 1975; Lake, Stryker, and Wyckoff-Bennett homesteads.
  - Greenpoint (Box 17, Folder 28)
    Debevoise house; Newtown Creek; McGolrick Park.
  - Hospitals (Box 17, Folder 29)
    Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital (some items gift of Paul Castellon, 1976); Long Island College Hospital (set of June 1983 images numbered V1998.025); Graham Institute for Aged Females.
  - Interiors - By address (Box 18, Folder 1)
    295 Sterling Place; 22 Halsey Street; John J. Hill home, 301 Hicks Street; 44 Linden Street; 42 Bartlett Street. Note that an image of the exterior of 42 Bartlett Street is housed in Street Scenes and Buildings.
  - Interiors - Unidentified (Box 18, Folder 2, Box 21)
  - Italian Americans (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Giglio festival and Italian food stores circa 1980s.
  - Landscapes (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Libraries (Box 18, Folder 5)
    One image of proposed (never completed) Central library (Brooklyn Public Library).
  - Long Island (Box 18, Folder 6, Box 24)
  - Manhattan (Box 18, Folder 7, Box 24)
  - Maps (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Memorials, Markers, and Gravestones (Box 18, Folder 9, Box 24)
    Includes Prison Ship Martyrs' Monument at Fort Greene Park.
  - Midwood (Box 18, Folder 10)
    One image of Midwood Club, Flatbush Avenue.
  - Military (Box 21, Folder 1-2, Box 25)
  - Mill Basin (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Schenk homestead.
  - Motion Pictures (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Museums (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Brooklyn Museum; Brooklyn Children's Museum; MoMA P.S. 1
  - Navy, Underwood & Underwood (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - New Utrecht (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - New York State (Box 18, Folder 17, Box 25)
  - Parades (Box 18, Folder 18)
    Includes a set of images of the Brooklyn Heights Historic Parade, crica 1984, gift of Adelay Liss, executrix of Robert Kahn's estate.
  - Park Slope (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Several images of the Cortelyou house/Old Stone House; homes on 5th Street and 8th Avenue; apartment building at 118 8th Avenue.
  - Parks (Box 18, Folder 20)
    1868 design for layout of Fort Greene Park from Manual of the Common Council of the City of Brooklyn.
  - Prisons (Box 18, Folder 21)
    Two images of Kings County Penitentiary and several of the penitentiary at Blackwell's Island.
  - Prospect Park (Box 18, Folder 22, Box 27, Box 25)
    Several color photos of a reenactment of the Battle of Brooklyn; Lefferts homestead; Litchfield villa; Boat House. Some images gift of Dorothy A. Burns.
    Box 29 contains a 3' long rolled panoramic photo of Charles Lindbergh addressing a crowd at Prospect Park in June 1927.
    The photograph in Box 29 is rolled and may be inaccessible to researchers.
  - Prospect Park - Grand Army Plaza (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Two photographs in this folder depict the statue being installed on top of the arch and were the gift of Patricia Knox. One image of the plaza from above was the gift of the Bronx Historical Society.
  - Prospect Park - Plans and Drawings (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Replica of Mount Vernon; Dairy; Lullwood bridge; Concert Grove house; well and boiler house; observatory; parade ground lodge and shelter; Bartel Pritchard square; Eastern Parkway.
  - Prospect Park - Zoo (Box 19, Folder 3)
    One photograph: meeting at Borough Hall in June 1935: Robert Moses, Alfred E. Smith, Raymond V. Ingersoll, and Louis C. Wills (chairman of Prospect Park Zoo committee). Planning the raising of funds for the procurement of animals.
  - Prospect-Lefferts Gardens (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Queens (Box 19, Folder 5, Box 24, Box 25)
  - Rallies, mid-1990s (Box 19, Folder 6)
    One set of color photos of a Protect the Arts rally to "keep culture in NYC - stop 100% cuts to arts programs," mid-1990s.
  - Red Hook (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Erie Basin; Atlantic docks; Red Hook Houses; Battery tunnel.
  - Religion - Judaism (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Russian Americans (Box 19, Folder 9)
    One image of Black Sea Bookstore, Inc.
  - Schools (Box 19, Folder 10, Box 22, Box 25)
    Erasmus; Pratt; Adelphi; Packer; Church of the Pilgrims; P.H.H. nursing; International School of Music; P.S. 179 (June 1920); Mark Hopkins JHS (January 1944; V1997.033); P.S. 102 (June 1941; 2004.013; Gift of Rosary Gilheany [nee Scacciaferro]); Prospect Heights Presbyterian Sabbath School.
    The photograph from P.S. 179 is rolled and inaccessible to researchers.
  - Sheepshead Bay (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Three of the photographs in this folder are labeled "Saul Goldsmith collection."
  - Shipping Industry (Box 19, Folder 12)
    One of the photographs in this folder is labeled "Schwartz collection."
  - Ships (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Includes photographs by seaman Irving Mordkowitz of surrender ship USS Missouri (built Brooklyn Navy Yard) returning for the last time, October 1947. Also includes a photograph of the Indiana in dry dock, Brooklyn Navy Yard, October 1898, gift of Isabelle L. Ivory, 1949.
  - Sports and Recreation - Acting and Theater (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sports and Recreation - Athletics, Underwood & Underwood (Box 19, Folder 15, Box 21, Folder 3)
    Mostly baseball teams and players, and one image of Mrs. Leon M. Schoonmaker, a woman fencer.
  - Sports and Recreation - Children (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Includes a set of color photos of soccer teams in Red Hook circa 1995 and a black and white image of a toy sailboat race in Prospect Park.
  - Sports and Recreation - Gaming and Horseracing (Box 19, Folder 17)
    1977 photo of what appears to be a lottery winner taken by George Kanatous. Horseracing photos by Underwood & Underwood.
  - Staten Island (Box 19, Folder 18, Box 21, Folder 4)
    One color print of Staten Island quarantine in 1833 and one set of black and white photos of historic Staten Island buildings, 1885-1886, gift of E.M. Luidley.
  - Street Scenes and Buildings (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Buildings include 42 Bartlett Street (see also Interiors - Identified); A.J. Nutting and Co.; 663-667 Utica Avenue vacant lots, 1954 (Saul Goldsmith collection).